[Music]
he
hello good evening good day everybody I
hope you're doing great it's a new day
things have changed a lot since we last
spoke so yeah here we are the election
results are out and everything seems to
have Chang now so before we get into any
questions let me see who all is there on
the live chat as always so let's see who
all is
there I can see Terminator Karan yadov
shabri Eli deep kajal Sam Sam Satish
Yash ra johvi shabri Nan vikrant random
skull Vladimir vladimirovich Putin zuban
eang prit Agarwal SII Mishra Yash tiari
somi Jin somit mukarji Sonia
Sinha uh absence niharika Rahul push
ashutosh rajat ishan Sharma utkarsh Z om
beer hello doesn't matter Amisha hello
aush
anshul uh Dave tapan deep
999 absence fight and survive Dave tapan
those human beings weirdly flipping
wander ape radika adiya Karan nwat hello
Jay Shankar suan Singh param ruaj Amisha
Mishra hello again bishal Sumit Kumar
Shani ratna taru panda aay
zero with non joner Akash jant laa lakpa
lakpa barab Vishal hardik deep tripti
omprakash Sagar shiram Dave Etc
everybody else ntin Nama Chandra
shikari mavin sanket Malik Sayad C
stubbor Roshan Tanish rajat chobra hello
tanmai Arijit and everybody else Dr J
Shankar hello
Shar jnv and everybody else ton verti
okay I'm going to stop uh I'm going to
stop greeting everybody and let's get on
with the questions so what questions do
we have ask me the questions ask me the
questions we shall take up the questions
let's
go VM says this election has given a
shock shock to the BJP with them now not
holding an absolute majority in the Lo
saaba will this impact any important
decision
made by the government now of course it
will impact major decisions important
decisions that will be made by the
government now this is no longer the the
era of the
BJP as a standalone party this is not a
victory for the BJP this is a victory
for the NDA the BJP what got what 240
seats they were talking about 400 they
got 240 or so seats which is short well
short of the 273 mark which is one past
the the halfway mark so now they're
going to have to depend on other parties
one is the tel one is the Chandra Babu
NAU's party Mr Chandra Babu NAU's party
one is Mr nitish Kumar's party and there
are other smaller parties here and there
they're going to have to depend on that
and the two big ones are Mr naidu's
party and Mr NES Kumar's party and
they're going to extract concessions
from Mr Modi they're going to do that
they the ball is in their court now so
they're going to ask for for very
important Ministries and what not we
don't know they're going to ask for all
that and every major decision every
important decision policy decision or
whatever the government does Mr Modi
does going forward next five years
they're going to want to have a say in
everything they're going to extract
everything of value that they
can so we're not going to see a strong
powerful Mr Modi this time we're going
to see a weak Mr Modi
this is this is the
truth exactly what it is Mr Modi is no
longer going to be that strong all all
you know that that that great leader
that we had the past 10 years is going
to be a much weaker a diminished
leader and we're going to have U this
may impact various decisions made by the
government I don't think it'll impact
foreign policy too
much uh I don't think it will impact the
economic policy too much but yes this
these parties will have a say in that
and when you have other parties coming
into the mix whichever it is it's more
than these two that I just named there
are multiple parties here when you have
other parties in a coalition there's
always the possibility of foreign
interference external
interference and so on all right so
that's where we are it will certainly
have some kind of an impact on the
policies that the government frames this
this time around the next five years the
major decisions to make and so on what
Ministries they are forced to give to
these small parties they're going to ask
for as as much as they can and yeah so
that's where we are so it was this a
shock this the election results were
were this a shock well if you watch my
podcast for example the latest podcast
that I have with Dr caval Cil in which I
ask him what could be the policies of
the Modi 3.0 government in which I say
hopefully Mr Modi comes to power so I am
already
expressing some amount of worry like you
all know I always said that I want Mr
Modi to win but I was worried even when
I was recording the podcast with Dr Cil
and you will see me saying similar
things at other points in time also so I
have been worried about whether the BJP
I was saying I'll be happy if the BJP
reaches 273 just there that's enough I
don't want 4003 20 350 whatever just
reach 273 it's not happened and who do
they have to blame are they going to
blame the Indian voter are they going to
blame the people of India hey come on
the buck stops at the
top they only have themselves to blame
so I wasn't surprised by the results
that much it kind of I'm I'm just glad
that the NDA has got a majority even
though it means that Mr Modi is now a
weak prime minister well who does he
have to blame for this so yes there we
are
okay uh my message to Indian voters well
we've got five years to go for the next
elections I would say look my message to
the Indian voters is you have to vote
for what is best for the country don't
vote emotionally Lo emotionally vote
logically think of the bigger picture
what is best for the country yes it is
true that the BJP and Mr Modi and
whoever else is is part of the mix they
may not have fulfilled all of your
wishes and desires and they may have
taken actions and steps that you don't
like but overall who's best for the
country that's how you have to vote you
have to set your personal emotions and
aspirations apart sometimes and think of
what is best for the country okay I did
not get what I desired but overall which
party which leader is best for the
country and that's how you
vote and you may be aware that I have
not said uttered a single vot of
criticism of Mr Modi in the past 10
years it's not like I have been happy
with everything he's been doing there's
a lot of frustration but if you ask me
to vote today again I'll still vote for
Mr Modi so that's what I would say you
have to vote considering keeping the
national interest at the Forefront not
your particular cast aspirations or your
local thing or whatever it is that is my
message and obviously you have to
understand history if you don't know the
history of the past 20 years 30 years 50
years then you will not know who has
been
turning this nation into a
mess there are so many examples of this
in this particular election where people
have voted for the ones who have made
their life miserable but that's just the
Indian voter so I would not blame the
Indian voter the Indian voter is the way
the Indian voter is it's because your
education system is garbage it is rotten
so people don't know how to think
critically people don't know true
history so they will vote according to
their whims and fances and
emotions so what can I say it is what it
is
saes says why did the BJP lose aoda of
all the places well that's a good
question why did the BJP lose aoda maybe
it's time to speak about this why did
the BJP lose aoda aodha is the place
where the ram jomi is where the ram Mand
has been rebuilt after a gap of almost
500 years Mr Modi went ahead and did the
pran pratita in February or so this year
so the people of and the city has been
renovated kind of I mean there there are
better roads and all so why did the
people reject the BJP and give them such
a big slap in the face why there has to
be
reasons there are lots of
reasons so overall I can tell you why
the BJP could not reach 273 but first of
all aoda so look I am not from aoda I
have never visited aoda uh but what I
hear is that there have been many things
that went
wrong first of all the city apparently
doesn't have a good sewerage system and
now there's a lot of footfalls in the
city people Pilgrims from all over the
country all over the world are coming in
Hindus to visit the ram Mand and this is
placing an additional burden on the city
which already doesn't have a good seage
system then uh lots of you
know if you see any historic
temple anywhere Hindu temple or dharmic
Temple anywhere in the world you will
see let me give you example instead of
just giving you a you know lectures so
let's go to Google and let's let's
Google some temples let's try and
understand how what a temple is like
okay
so pranan Temple Indonesia right I think
it's in
Indonesia so if you look at this ancient
Hindu temple in Indonesia which is about
a thousand years old you see it's not
just one Temple it's a complex of
temples okay uh can we see it from the
air look at this it is one giant temple
four five other 1 2 3 four five other
smaller temples and a whole complex of
smaller structures all around it you can
see that
clearly this will give you an even
better view it's it's not just one
building we're talking about it's a
whole complex of buildings all around it
what about uh
Anor Anor Temple which is another Hindu
temple which is in Cambodia now if you
look at this once again it's not just
one structure it's a whole complex of
buildings that's how a Hindu temple
always is it is not just one building
it's a whole complex of
buildings around the main structure and
you will see this all over the place you
will see this in in Buddhist temples in
stupas
ETC and so on now the ram Mand has been
built but around that the holy place the
ram
janabi you had so many other older
temples smaller temples that had come up
over the centuries centuries I'm not
talking about the far past 5 10 20 30 50
years these temples had been around for
centuries and these were all most of
these were
demolished to make space for the big
Temple so it was turned into an
architectural project and the cultural
civilization sensitivity was were all
thrown out thrown out of the window I
guess it is some genius level IAS
officers who must have decided this or
whoever else okay the IAS people most of
them are a deracinated lot I'm sure
there are lots of good people also but
majority I know are kind of a
deracinated lot they they grow up study
you know reading Roma taper and inhib
and all that so that was done and then
lots of buildings were demolished homes
were demolished people were not given
proper compensation there are so many
issues they this was not handled
properly and there have been uh lots of
there's been a lot of criticism about
the way the pran pratia was done the day
dates when it was done I mean and so on
I mean there's so many things that went
into this so overall the people of aoda
it looks like they were significantly
unhappy with the way things have been
done and they expressed themselves in
the only way the Indian person Indian
citizen can you say something nobody
will listen to you so you vote so yeah
there you have it there you have it
that's what happened okay let's talk
about the election some more and then I
will take other questions as well
uh chirag ATI says if after the next
five years some other government some
other party comes to power will the ruin
all the progress of Modi of the past 10
15 years how will it affect impact India
the moment one of the older parties come
to power comes to power whether it is
one party or a coalition of parties they
will within weeks undo everything that
Mr Modi has done in the past 10 years
within weeks it will be undone okay and
Mr Modi in the past 10 years has not
touched a single word in the Indian
education system the moment these people
come to power in a matter of days or
weeks they will reform in their way the
Indian education system in such a way
that it will take India back another 100
200 years that's how fast they act and
the BJP did nothing over the past 10
years I have been so frustrated about
this I've spoken about this I've got two
or three episodes of asit only about the
education system 38 39 whatever number
it was I don't remember now so yeah so
that's what they do they will undo
everything so it's it's just the grace
of the gods that at least the NDA has
gone past 273 272 273 the BJP has been
unable to do it the Modi wave is over
the Modi tsunami is over but yeah so it
will be a disaster for for India and
even now it's going to be a weak Mr Modi
and a weak government of India and yeah
we will not the economy perhaps won't
grow the way it was one hoped it would
so who do we blame for this do we blame
the Indian voter I mean the Indian voter
we know who the Indian voter
is all right let's see something else
rajat says will India be unsafe in the
next five years and how will the Foreign
Relations we built in the past 10 years
suffer what should the common Indians do
it looks like dark days are coming look
let's not be so pessimistic I don't
think dark days are coming yet and I
don't think the foreign policy will
change too much obviously Nations like
the us are going to uh negotiate much
harder with India they're going to press
India much harder because this is going
to be a weaker Mr Modi a weaker
government and uh there will Mr Modi
will have less room to maneuver because
of the pressure of his own allies in the
NDA because they will want to extract as
much as possible from him and I don't
blame them that's the way politics works
that's the way uh you know electoral
democracy in the West Minister system
works so I don't blame them for that so
he has placed himself in this this
position position Mr Modi by claiming
that I will get 400 this time have some
humility sir I'm a wellwisher I have not
said a single word of criticism in the
past 10 years but here we are so I don't
think India will be unsafe foreign
relations are going to change some more
the US and Nations like the US Etc even
Russia even China are going to negotiate
much harder with India they're going to
press India much more and the danger is
that if Mr Modi doesn't have sufficient
room to negotiate um
doesn't have sufficient maneuvering
space because of the Coalition partners
then India may become like the EU
Nations and might have to you know uh
give concessions to the US so when you
are not a very strong when you don't
have a very strong government with a lot
of room to maneuver you get placed in
such positions so that is the danger we
have that we become a wasal of the US
there is a possibility well I hope it
doesn't happen I hope Mr Modi still has
a strong for policy it's possible that
the that the alliance Partners will only
want concessions in whatever it is at
the domestic level and hopefully not at
the foreign policy level so as long as
there is there we will be fine but yeah
foreign policy there could be less room
to maneuver for Mr Modi and economically
there could be this could somehow in
some way perhaps possibly hopefully not
but possibly hamper India's economic
growth so instead of growing at around
8% which we are doing for the past
couple of quarters or whatever it is
we've been growing in excess of
expectations now we may be growing at 5%
5 and a half% or something which would
be bad for us we want to grow as fast as
possible as long as possible so yeah
that's where we are so India I don't
think India will be unsafe oh the US
will pressurize India to normalize
relations with Pakistan for sure they
will pressurize India they'll pressurize
Mr Modi to normalize relations with
Pakistan now it depends on how much
leverage they have and whether they can
if they have any any
let's say backdoor Channels with the
alliance partners then they could uh
make the alliance Partners make
unreasonable demands which would uh
Place more pressure on Mr Modi and by
doing that by applying pressure from
various fronts you could make Mr Modi do
things he would otherwise never want to
do Mr Modi has been ignoring Pakistan
completely for the past five or so years
now he may be forced perhaps I'm
speculating entire this is entire
complete speculation but the Americans
will want to weaken India from v a
variety of
friends so this is this is now the
prospect that we are staring at I am
still optimistic I I'm I'm still
optimistic that Mr Modi will be able to
handle the alliance Partners they will
also be reasonably
reasonable reasonably reason reasonable
and hopefully things go well it all
depends on how Mr Modi and his his his
people Mr sha Etc they they deal with
this but overall it's not it's not the
ideal situation what should common
Indians do pray my dear friends pray
pray now it's not no longer in your
hands you the janata janardan like Mr
Modi says have
voted so now reap the benefits of what
you have done I I don't think my viewers
have have voted in this manner but what
can I
say Dr Jo Shankar says what are your
thoughts on amritpal sing's Victory
being with him being a khalistani will
you reap what you
saw it was very well known that this
khalistani sentiment was being nurtured
by the five eyes Nations which is led by
the US this has been happening for such
a long time was Mr Modi not aware of
this was the government not aware of
this and was any action taken to nip
this in the bud no you keep appeasing
them right when these this
uh when when the farm laws were were
brought in which were good laws and
these people come and start blockading
roads these fake Farmers these
billionaire farmers who come in Mercedes
and SUVs you give into them and you give
them such a big boost that we can now
hold the country to ransom they come
into Delhi the Delhi riots happen they
they climb on the Red Fort you do
nothing nobody is jailed then obviously
these people will will be emboldened and
now you have actual khalistan is being
being elected elected to the government
who do we blame for this I blame Mr Modi
and his government they should have been
stronger I still think Mr Modi is the
right Right leader for us these five
years but this is entirely who is to
blame who who else is to
blame at the end of the day it's the
leadership that is to blame for whatever
goes wrong you can't blame the people of
India so it is very unfortunate this is
very dangerous thing for India and now
this is going this is going to be fueled
even more by the United States and the
five wise Nations they are the ones who
have kept this khalistan nonsense going
on for all these years they are the ones
who funded and financed all this
terrorism in India in the 80s and
whatnot the Pakistani terrorism the
khalistani terrorism all that they
funded this and they have allegedly
created political parties in certain
parts of India they allegedly are
playing subnational diplomacy tactics in
various parts of India they allegedly
are funding certain political parties
and certain movements allegedly in India
all alleged we have no real evidence but
patterns May allegedly look like that so
this is going to happen more now now we
have khalistanis in in Parliament okay
congratulations good job sir good job
what can I
say yeah it's very
unfortunate Primal Raj says will all big
ticket reforms not
happen look Mr Modi had 10 years a
godamn decade for doing big Bank
reforms what yeah we have I mean you
cannot take away from what he has done
uh you know bank accounts for everybody
everybody has that various schemes that
have benefited the poor people so much
roads Railways infrastructure being
built railway lines being built highways
being built at break neck breake neck
pace so many they've doubled the number
of airports they have tremendously
strengthened the northern boundaries
with Chinese occupied Tibet and given
the the Armed Forces whatever they need
all these things I really commend the
government but big ticket what what else
is left right I mean there is so much
that they could have done by now but
they have not done I mean what
about what about illegal
immigration when was that big ticket
reform going to happen there are ringas
and Bangladesh is all over the big
cities of India all the ralas all the
puncture Wallas all the whatever Wallas
are now they all speak Bengali now
they're all over the country when Mr
Modi was campaigning for the 24 ele 2014
election he had gone to Assam and he had
said he had said the illegal Bangladesh
is Bor b b because once I am elected you
guys are out well tell me how many of
them have been
evicted how many what was done was the
government not aware of the disastrous
disastrous demographic change that's
happening it is being done on a daily
basis they're still coming in what has
been done to change
that
nothing now now what happens the entire
country's demographics are changing the
census also hasn't happened so we are
Flying Blind we don't even know how many
Bangladesh are there about 10 years ago
they were saying five crores 50 lakhs
sorry 50 million 50 million Bangladeshi
illegal infiltrators inside India today
the number was double what was done
about that
nothing H it is so frustrating how much
of a big chance Mr Modi had to clean up
these things nothing was done the
education system is trash it is garbage
the Indian people the Indian voter
doesn't have the ability to think
critically they vote based on emotions
and small Petty sentiments and don't
blame them for that how do you how do
you fix this you fix it by change by
reforming the education system 10 years
they had 10 years and they did not
change of word now there have there is
something called the what the new
education policy which is nothing which
is which does not address any of the
real issues in the education system I
had the chairman of the ugc I asked him
to explain what the are what the what
the new education policy is I did not
get any real answers from him so there's
nothing that's been done none of these
big bang reforms have happened
civilizational issues have been totally
ignored people who will never vote for
the country and for the BJP have been
appeased
constantly the general category people
have been marginalized what I mean there
so much so much so I don't see any big
ticket reforms happening now next five
years the education system they will
stay far away from that so now you your
children will keep on being taught
anti-national nonsense they will keep on
being
deracinated generation after generation
fake history will still be taught
distorted history will still be taught
they will not be taught how to think
they will be told what to think and so
on that's where we are huge opportunity
lost good job
congratulations so yeah I don't see any
big ticket reforms happening now but at
least we're not going to backslide the
way we would have if some other party
had come to power you you know which
one
okay uh are BJP advisers to blame here I
don't know who advisers and all that I
don't really look in in great depth into
National politics I look at geopolitics
and look at all that stuff so I don't
know I don't analyze this but clearly
somebody is to blame I mean I don't
blame the top leaders of the BJP 10
years in power they don't have their ear
to the ground but you need to have a
mechanism by which you have people who
know what's happening on the ground what
the people are frustrated about what the
people want what they need what are the
demands what are what are the
requirements and pass that on up there
it looks like there was a disconnect so
and who do I blame do I blame the people
down there or do the blame the leader
leadership for not putting for not
putting the right structures in place I
blame the leadership you don't blame
those below you the leader has to take
the blame so I don't blame the BJP
advisers I don't blame whoever I blame
the top leadership they have messed up
at least 272 you could have got but you
were claiming to some what Charo par
have some
humility yeah
says now we got to deal with it we got
to deal with it now
uh yeah let's let's take more questions
this is I mean very unfortunate but at
least you should thank the gods that
it's not the worst possible scenario Mr
Modi is still around hopefully he does
something good okay let's take this
question aru says whose wasal are the
asan countries they are wasal of the
greatest Empire in the world the United
States that's the simple straightforward
answer and you may not see the linkages
but it's there
so yes they are not entirely Sovereign
Nations they are vasal I mean look at
for example a nation that I really like
a lot which is swabi or
Thailand uh very beautiful Nation
beautiful culture they are more Indian
than us you go there you don't feel any
culture shock okay you they look
different from us but they are more
Indian than us culturally they they they
tradition they cherish Indian culture
and traditions as their own and they are
much more upfront in displaying that
everywhere than we are we are
secularists aren't aren't we so let's
take the example of
Thailand in
Thailand the you have seen in the past
various student demonstrations that
happen all of a sudden across the
country in a coordinated coordinated
Manner and who do you see what kind of
students green head redhead pinkhead
students coming up and demonstrating
against the government is a pressure
tactic you see that happening on demand
the threat of a color Revolution by
putting this out on the on on the
streets so yeah it's just one example
all these nations and then there is the
geopolitical meddling in Burma which is
it's not an asan country it's a
Southeast Asian country and that's
spilling over into India it's another
pressure tactic for India on India so
these nations they are all they would
they I I Pro promise you they would wish
that India was stronger and they could
be under India's protection and
domination because India is not a hegic
nation the US is
so yeah they are all
wasal of the
US uh Sonia says uh the west and its
lack of culture is spreading like wild
wild like wildfire yes they are trying
to spread that everywhere across the
world what they call bism whatever they
call whatever is currently their their
pet project they want that to spread all
over the world and they have means and
mechanisms and Vector vectors by which
they spread this and they're doing it in
India also they have various agencies in
not agencies agents Etc within India
assets within India now we have we're
going to have uh foreign universities
setting up shop in India enjoy that I
would say that India should ensure that
they only teach Science and Technology
and Engineering we don't need your
godamn Humanities and all but I am sure
that the government will allow all this
nonsense to come in I I be I I I will be
the happiest person to be proven wrong
here but I fear that the government of
India is going to allow these foreign
universities to teach the humanities in
India we don't need that you have a
degree in Humanities what do you produce
what do you produce what do you produce
for society you produce nonsense you
produce wokeism and V voke ideas it's
like a virus when you have a degree in
engineering you produce something
valuable and
tangible so I don't know why we would
need these universities to teach the
humanities in India but I am I'm pretty
sure it's going to happen I hope I wrong
I'll be the happiest person to eat my
words to be forced to eat my words I'll
not be forced to do it I'll do it
willingly and happily but that's what I
fear so yeah that's where we
are all right let's let's take some
other
questions uh okay Malik say says if the
US has really has oil reserves then why
do they waste their power in the Middle
East nurturing VES like Israel Saudi
also some say that us Bluff about oil
reserves uh the US has gigantic oil
reserves now and this is all Shale oil
and it's extracted via a process called
fracking which is very bad for the
environment but it is what it is and the
US is now not just self-sufficient it's
probably the world's number one producer
of oil today and Canada also has
significant Shale oil and other sorts of
oil and gas reserves so they have this
so the question is why do they waste
their power energy Etc in the Middle
East nurturing vasal like Saudi Arabia
and so on well historically they had to
do this because historically they did
not know the technology to extract oil
from Shale Etc did not exist until the
last two decades so historically they
had to depend on the middle east region
for their energy supplies and that's why
it was vital for them to control the
entire region and keep it Ablaze all the
time and that's why the Middle East has
always been in crisis for decades since
the 1920s 30s 40s and so on the west has
done that so and when you have that
structure in place when all these
nations that you have turned them into
vasal why would you give that up why is
the US a superpower because it has vasal
all over the place all over the world
because it has military bases everywhere
it has more than
800 extra territorial military bases
which is military bases which are us in
origin which are owned by the US and
operated by the us but which are not on
US Territory they are on the territories
of other nations why would you give
something like that up why you have that
you don't give it up you extend that you
expand that Network so any
self-respecting power would only expand
their sphere of influence and their
power projection capabilities they would
never let that shrink so that's why it's
not wasting power that augments that
power they you know having this wasal
having this military base in the Middle
East it augments us power it makes them
more
powerful so it's these extr territorial
military bases which is the basis of
their power projection firstly and
secondly it is there the US dollar
status is the world's Reserve currency
these two things make the US the
superpower the sole superpower what what
is different between the US and the and
Russia power projection Russia has no
power projection nothing compared to
what the US has and the US has the
world's Reserve currency currency the
the Russians don't have that so that's
why Russia is not a superpower despite
having the world's scariest and largest
stockpile of nuclear
warheads so yeah so that's why they do
this and they they're not bluffing about
their oil reserves they do have that for
sure okay radika says Modi did
everything for India I agree the man to
to the fullest extent of his capability
has served India he's taken not he's not
taken a single day off he sleeps three
four hours a day that's what one hears
and he truly has been serving India so
no no criticism of that whatsoever
you cannot you cannot question his
dedication you can't question his work
ethic you can't question his sacrificing
everything for the country no doubt
about it so yes Modi did everything for
India totally agree do you feel we are
divided into States and can't look
beyond that a developed India 2047 is
not our concern that's why we were ruled
by others for so long I agree we are
divided into States on a linguistic
basis you should you know I have a
podcast on this channel with Dr go goam
Desi Raju in which he Advocates that
India should be divided into about 75 or
so States smaller
States okay and lots of people don't
like it oh you are breaking out breaking
Tamil Nadu into multiple States you are
trying to divid and Rule no you idiots
it's not that it gives better governance
a smaller state in a smaller State you
have better governance because every
person is closer in proximity to power
and and there's a lot of things into
that so we have been divided into states
and these states have been drawn on the
basis of linguistics so it pits one
State against another on on a linguistic
basis it's us against them and then you
have the so-called cast politics and
whatnot and Indians because of the
education system can't look beyond the
end of their nose because they have not
been allowed to learn how to think
critically the only the only thing you
learn in the education system is how to
bow down in Deer to Authority who you
perceive as an authority so the
education system is trash it is garbage
and Mr Modi had 10 years to change it
he's not done that so yeah he you cannot
question his work ethic he has spent his
entire the past decade simply working
working working for India but he could
have done
better okay yeah I agree that the Indian
economy has needs to have the first
priority full Focus but you have
Ministries who can take care of culture
who can take care of Education why
weren't they doing what they were
supposed to do they didn't do
it so yeah and of course the people of
India because they don't understand they
don't realize how much under threat
India is because they are completely
deracinated they have no connection with
Indian culture because the education
system doesn't teach India's culture so
they feel that India's culture is some
Far Away alien thing which have which
existed in some other time period and it
has nothing to do with us no
relevance
so that's what it is and and people are
concerned about small Petty matters
closer to home and they don't see the
big picture that this that we are part
of an ancient civilization we have to
redevelop and so on so that yeah I agree
because because of this because of such
this is one of the things that
contributed to us being ruled by others
for so long and these others they
created this device in society they
imposed this education system on us and
after 47 we have been continuing that
and after 2014 also we continued that
nothing was done to change that so that
is deeply frustrating and that's why we
that's where we are I would like to see
if developed India by 2047 we still have
time what 20 23 years A lot can happen
but we will need the right leadership we
will need a strong leadership Modi 3.0
is a is a is a time period in which
we're going to have a weak leadership in
India because it's going to be a
coalition government Mr Modi will be a
diminished leader a weak leader it is
now time to start thinking of who comes
next and from my perspective the only
person I don't see Mr Dr J Shankar being
the next prime minister of India are you
kidding me he's not the next prime he's
not prime minister material let's be
very clear Dr Jo Shankar is not prime
minister material he's a diplomat he's
good at that he's great at that nothing
nothing more than that I don't see Mr
Amit sha as the right prime minister for
India next or whoever else I think the
only person that I that gives me hope is
Mr
Yogi so now the question is will he be
the Prime Minister candidate in 29 will
that happen when Mr Modi wanted to be
prime minister candidate in 2009 the we
know what happened the adwani faction in
the BJP uh marginalized him in 2014 also
Mr Modi he had to fight so hard to
become the Prime Minister candidate the
adwani faction again who Mr adwani was
Mr modi's mentor and he tried to
marginalize Mr Modi and prevent him from
being the Prime Minister candidate so
there's always this problem when when
there's the time for a power transition
so will Mr Modi make it really hard for
Mr Modi for for Mr Yogi to come to power
or to at least become the next candidate
it's possible we don't know there's all
kinds of stuff that goes into politics
but uh I think it's time for us to start
looking Beyond Mr Modi because Mr Modi
3.0 is going to be a much diminished
prime minister and that's just a fact
okay if it hurts your feelings so be it
I'm just telling you facts I support Mr
Modi I wanted him to get at least get go
past 273 he did not he failed and I'm
I'm just glad that the NDA still has a
majority and he's going to it's going to
continue for some
time uh Mr Kat says can you imagine the
scenario where you where you have US
military bases in Sri Lanka the US can
make it happen if they want to uh that
would create friction between the US and
India but the US is just way too strong
so it can happen it can happen they
already have military bases in uh in the
chos archipelago Diego Garcia which is
illegal occupied and own occupied by the
UK and the US the Americans wanted a
military base on on an island of the
coast of
Bangladesh and they they had told Miss
shik
Hina that you give the give us this
island you allow us to make a military
base here and we will not interfere in
your
election okay and at that time we had a
strong government in India Modi 2.0 so
Mr Modi gave his support full support to
miss Hina and the Americans were not
able to interfere fear in the Bangladesh
elections and she was able to win
again and the Americans have not got
their military base there but they want
it now we have a weak government in
India weaker government not entirely
weak like Manan Singh but it's a weaker
government so let's see what goes now
but it can happen the Americans can make
it
happen all
right
um shiv says the sad reality of this ele
election is that an IPS officer Mr
anamalai for
IPS officer Mr anamalai lost the
election and a khalistani won the
election where is bat heading
towards yeah yeah well well said Mr
anamalai is a former IPS officer uh but
see this is what happens because of
indoctrination and
brainwashing this is why why the
education system needs to be reformed
and was Mr Modi not aware of
this he had the chance he had 10 10
years a decade isn't it enough to reform
the education system to a certain extent
at least so that people understand what
at least we taught the right history the
correct history the truthful history
factual
history so we will know what happened
what happened in the 1970s and 80s who
was behind whatever happened and why
this cause is
wrong we bat is bat you can't break bhat
and we have these people within bat who
are now
going to sit in
Parliament it's it's not the fault of
the people I do not blame the voter the
voter he or she is simply doing what
they think is
right okay so you have to educate them
as to what is genuinely right for the
nation and the civilization not from me
from my petty little
perspective it is not all about me me me
it's about us but people don't
understand this because the education
system doesn't educate them it misleads
them so yes and that's why we have the
sad reality and who knows what more sad
realities we will
have uh yeah that's simply where we are
and and today we are in a situation
where YouTubers and
influencers can spread fake news
narratives and they are lapped up by
people in the
millions and some of these
influencers who are fake nationalists
are actually honored by the government
and given Awards and then they go later
on and say all eyes on
Rafa that's the kind of people the
government is is
honoring clueless people clueless the
government not the influencers the
influencers know what they're doing the
people in the government who are giving
honors and awards to such fake
nationalists
these opportunists these people in the
government are clueless utterly clueless
people they have no idea what's
happening so yes it's not the F fault of
the people of India it's not the fault
of the voter it is the fault of the
people in the leadership positions in
the government nobody else's
fault ah a historical question thank God
we are not talking about the elections
now harrai says do you think hanal bar
would have destroyed Rome if he had had
enough support and resources from kage
well that was the intention Hannibal
Bara invaded Rome and dealt a crushing
crushing defeat on on the Roman Legions
in a battle whose Name Escapes my mind
right now because it's been so long
since I read it read about it but his
intention was to end the threat from
Rome once and for all but he was not
supported from home he was not given the
resources and the uh replenishments and
whatever else he needed from carage they
backstabbed him they betrayed him and
that's why eventually he
failed and then we know what happened
eventually
K kage was destroyed once and for all
and it never came
back yes that's that's one of the
lessons we can learn from
history
okay sh sh Shiva says can the CAA and
UCC be implemented do you think Mr Modi
will be a strong enough prime minister
now with a coalition government to
implement controversial reforms
CAA should have been done long ago
should have been done when there was the
opportunity now I don't know UCC uniform
civil code I don't know I don't
know question marks question mark
question mark on UCC question mark on CA
both I don't know if they can be
implemented
mat Nami says how can we as Indians
protect Hinduism now that the Modi 3.0
is not as strong as they previously were
yesterday's results of BJP not getting
majority was a disaster yes it was a
disaster uh what can we do to protect
Hinduism you practice Hinduism that's
what you can do that is the best the
common person can do as you can see
there is the the Hindu temples are still
enslaved by the government all the
resources are are stolen by the
government appropriated by the
government and used for God knows what
so the Hindu temples are are still
enslaved and Mr Modi had 10 years to
change that he did
not and if you see if if you go to
Google Maps and go to any City any
Indian pilgrimage place like TI stals
and whatnot you will see a small one
Hindu temple and a number of religious
structures of other religions all
surrounding it so you will see today in
India in modern bhat the religious
structures of foreign religions are
cropping up everywhere there's so much
money behind this and you don't see new
Hindu temples Jane temples bod the
temples Etc coming up at all you see
what's happening in Punjab just see
what's happening in Punjab sik what
happened to the great SS what happened
to sik Pride it is painful to see what's
happening in Punjab so when I say Hindu
I mean all the dharmic paths all of them
so what can we do to PR to protect our
culture our Our civilizational Heritage
you have to practice Hinduism Buddhism
jism whatever it is that you follow
practice it keep it alive teach teach it
to your friends to teach it to your
children those who are on the same path
as you I mean at least nominally that's
what you have to do the government is
not going to help you it's entirely in
your hands the government should have
been helping you after all you voted
them into power but they chose not to Mr
Modi chose to appease those who will
never vote for him repeatedly again and
again and again and when something
happens to your
people your problem kakas get chopped up
in various States their
problem and so on and so on so it the
the the government will not help you
your favorite politicians will not help
you whatever you want to do you have to
do it on your own but yeah you can are
you not strong enough are you not
numerous enough all you have to do is
coordinate Network and do what is right
that's
it mclin says is it time for
dictatorship well if you want a
dictatorship how do you implement one a
dictatorship is a tremendously powerful
leader in leadership with the en
structure around that
person yeah so people were saying that
India's democracy the West was claiming
the Western Nations New York Post and
what not Guardian BBC blah blah blah
blah blah they were claiming that
India's democracy is backsliding India's
becoming more authoritarian we are now
becoming less authoritarian if that was
authoritarianism Modi 2.0 now Modi 3.0
is what they like it's going to be a
weak
government is it time for dictatorship I
don't know
man uh well a strong much stronger
leadership and government would actually
be good for India it will accelerate the
changes that we need but yeah
not happening
now
okay vges says how do you manage to read
the news from all around the world and
also study history and science I'm
struggling to balance my studies with
news it's taking three hours a day to
read the news I don't read the news I
don't watch the news I don't remember
the last time I've watched a TV
debate okay I don't watch the news on TV
I don't watch any news channels I hardly
watch TV at all uh I don't spend a lot
of time on social media if you see my
Twitter there's hardly any tweets coming
out sometimes I retweet somebody else's
stuff because social media is an drain
on energy and time and whatnot and then
everything else how do
I how do I know what's happening in the
world I have certain sources that I look
at uh there are certain websites that I
glance at every day so that I know
what's happening if something is of some
pertinence or some interest I go and
read the article I read very very fast
okay I'm a very fast very rapid leader
reader
so I look at I glance at
headlines in various Publications about
half an hour in a day it takes me and
whatever strikes me or or stands out and
I know through from Decades of re
research what is pertinent what is not
so I look at that and if that's that's
interesting I go deeper into the rabbit
hole and and do that that's how I do it
it's a skill I developed over years and
years of of study and research and all
that that's how I do
it
okay um um um um
um chirag aast says why do Indians and
the West love democracy and secularism
so much can't India and the world grow
without democracy and secularism you
know democracy there is no real
democracy in the world there is no real
democracy in the world the US you think
it's a democracy it's a two-party System
One Step Above North Korea and China and
their policies are all the same with is
the Republicans or the Democrats they
have the same economic policies and the
same foreign policy the same military
policy and the same policy of of of
interfering in other nations internal
matters so it's actually a uni party
State actually the US it's it's an
authoritarian State masquerading as a
democracy but they claim to love
democracy so that they can use democracy
as a stick to beat you with they don't
love democracy they love to pretend to
love democracy Indians are enamored with
democracy India is a genuine democracy
but we are told that democ Cy is is in
danger what is more important the
national interest or your godamn
democracy is it is the national more
interest more important than your holy
book The
Constitution but this is what we are
taught this is why the education system
needs
reforms that's that's why I keep on
harping about the the need to reform the
Indian education system only then will
Indians truly realize what is really
important for the nation for the
civilization most Indians believe India
was born in 1947 most Indians believe
that we had founding
fathers most Indians believe that the
constitution is our holy book The
Constitution has not even been ratified
by the people of India it is an
illegitimate Constitution but if I say
that I get abusers and they mean well
they think that I'm I'm some
anti-national or something when I see
this okay I know they mean well and it
hurts them when someone says that the
constitution is illegitimate because
it's never been ratified because they
don't understand what it means so this
is the problem the education system
needs to be reformed so that Indians can
genuinely understand what the world is
about what the country is about what the
real history
is but it's not been done there was a
period of 10 years when Mr Modi could
have done something about it he chose to
completely ignore the issue and then
enjoy the rest of these five years and
let's see what happens next
okay harid says I want to talk I want to
ask about harana where on five seats BJP
won and and five Congress won according
to you who's going to form government
there uh I'm so sorry I do not know I
I I don't I'm not a political analyst
okay I don't look at each state in the
structure cast structure and seat
structure and how many people which
party has had historically stronghold in
which seat I don't look at that I have
absolutely no idea I certainly can
become really good at that if I put my
mind to it but it doesn't really
interest me that much I am interested in
the National interest in in geopolitics
that's what interests me you ask me
about that I can answer this I'm so
sorry I apologize but I don't know so I
can't answer your question I I hope yeah
that's just what it
is um
Annabeth Jackson says how was Nepal
separated from India see Nepal was part
of what we call bhat wassh ancient
historical India as a civilizational
entity and Nepal was one of the kingdoms
and the kingdom of the modern Kingdom of
Nepal it owes its origin to the uh
conquests and the great activities of of
that what is that guy's
name PR Narayan sha I think yes in the
18th century in which he Capt he
conquered the Nar Valley and established
a kingdom there and expanded his kingdom
and that became what we call Nepal today
historically it's always been part of
bat was the people of Nepal are the same
as us culturally ethnically
linguistically civilization everything
linguistically of course we understand
each other just by speaking we don't
have to uh talk to each other in English
or
whatever now what happened is that the
British the when they occupied India for
two two and a half centuries uh there
were there were times when Tibet had
become very weak and you would have some
Chinese presence and whatnot over there
and there was obviously the the great
game happening in the 19th century where
Russia was trying to make inroads and
and and come closer to India and so on
so the British needed a buffer state in
the region so they allowed the kingdom
of Nepal to remain independent even
though they were completely in control
of its Imports exports its economy and
all that the British were completely in
control of Nepal's Imports exports and
so on but they allowed Nepal to remain
nominally independent and outside of the
British Raj okay and after 1947 when
India became uh India became a dominan
Dominion of the UK and then then later
India became a rep Republic Nepal wanted
to rejoin India uh the king of
Nepal wanted he actually proposed to Mr
Neo that Nepal should become one of the
states of India and Mr n rejected that
I don't make this claim read uh one of
the books by our former president Mr uh
Mr mukarji pranab mukarji he writes
about this it's been written about it's
been written in in you know in many
Publications and so on I don't have the
links right now other I would put it up
but yeah so Nepal wasn't separated as
such from India the nation state of
India was created as an artificial
nation state instead of a civilizational
entity it was it was downgraded to a
nation state in
1947 it became a republic in 1950 and
Nepal never became part of
that and that's just what happened
historically we had kingdoms Nepal was
part of various Indian Empires like the
Gupta Empire the the the the kusan
Empire the Moria Empire other Empires as
well the Kota Empire it's been part of
various Indian Empires and dynasties and
rules I mean you know
Queen Sia Davi SAA was was from was born
in what Nepal was in present day Nepal
Lord Buddha goam Buddha was born and
present in Nepal lumini and so on
so historically it's it's all been the
same thing so yeah that's kind of what
happened what's your opinion says Atul
about BJP opening account Kerala I'm
glad it happened I think there one seat
that the BJP won in Kerala good I'm glad
it it happened a little bit of Silver
Lining somewhere for the
BJP Rohit Singh says should Indians
start speaking Indian languages like the
Russians and the Chinese speak their own
language Indians should do it but we are
not allowed to do it because you speak
Indian languages and prioritize that
then you will not speak good English if
you don't speak good English you will
not be able to know what the code
decisions are you will not be able to
get a good job in any good Corporation
in so many drawbacks you speak a local
language you will be you will be called
a vernacular person H you don't speak
English to a certain extent accent
people will look down upon you the low
class low class low class and so on so
that's why Indians today see English
English is a Prestige language the same
way that Sanskrit used to be a Prestige
language all over Eastern Asia Etc even
today you go to Indonesia people have
Sanskrit names very strange combinations
of Islamic and Sanskrit names like
Muhammad Vishnu
and things like that but they still are
proud of their Heritage and we have just
given it up so um so yeah that's the
deal I would be the happiest person if
we so this
this this initiative has to come from
the government but the government is not
interested in doing anything that is
pertinent or or or related to culture
cultural issues I mean culture is very
important and uh civilizational issues
are very important you keep on pushing
that to the Future to the Future what's
going to happen is that you're going to
end up with a big deracinated population
who has no connection to their own
culture and then we when we try to
implement this at some point in time in
the future they will rebel against
you yeah so I agree that this should
happen but the government needs to to
take the
initiative Sada says is democracy the
really the right form of government for
India look at the past 2,000 years I've
said this in the past but I'll repeat
this just think of the past 2,000 3,000
years of Indian history and think about
the high points of Indian history the
morian Empire The kosan
Empire the Gupta Empire the Chola Empire
the marata Empire and I must have missed
a few but these are the high points of
Indian history where life was great for
the common Indian man woman and child
you had great living standards India was
powerful geopolitically and militarily
and India had so much influence on other
nations India was a net exporter large
scale exporter of
culture was India a democracy in those
times was India a democracy when Lord
Ram ruled India was India a democracy
when Lord Krishna ruled M matura ruled
over dwara
Etc was our one of our greatest Emperors
ashoke a Democrat was was he did he
believe in democracy did vishnugupta
chanaka believe in democracy did they
give Indians a great set of living
standards and something to be proud of
yes yes
yes so there's your answer and today
today we have democracy are you
satisfied with the India of today with
the standards that we have of in India
of today
yes uh
what should the Common Man of India be
doing now says doing now says rajat is
leaving India for a good for a while a
good plan what should the BJP do now to
secure 2029 look individually you should
do what is best for yourself okay if you
want to genuinely serve your country
first rise to the fullest extent of your
potential like I say if it involves
leaving India working outside of India
for a decade or two Do It Go and learn
everything you can acquire skills
acquire wealth acquire Fortune acquire
experience and then when you are the
best you can be if you choose you can
come back to India and contribute to the
country but to be able to contribute to
your nation your civilization you have
to first become a person of
substance and you have to find the best
way to become a person of substance the
optimal way of doing that and if you
have to leave the country and go and
settle down in another country for a few
years a decade or two by all means do
that okay by by all means do
that so that's the first answer what
should be the what should the Common Man
be doing now you should be raising your
standards investing in
yourselves the best way to do something
for the country is to first become a
person of substance invest in yourself
and those around you help those around
you but first help yourself only when
you become
genuinely powerful or wealthy or
something can you help more people so
invest in yourself raise your standards
don't be satisfied with what you have
and what you are that's what I would say
what should the BJP do now to secure
2029 the right leadership transition we
have to start looking Beyond Mr Modi Mr
Modi is
done Mr Modi is done he had 10 years to
do what he could he did what he could he
did a lot no doubt now it's going to be
a it's going to be a much diminished Mr
Modi he's already what 70 something in
2029 I don't want Mr Modi to stand for
election again he'll be too old for that
I think they have
to uh put the
right next next generation of leadership
in place now and not make it hard for
them to to for the transition to happen
so I would like to see Mr Yogi get more
PRI more more prominence now because if
you if you mess up if you mess up the
trans the the transition from one leader
to another it's going to be a disaster
it's it can actually end everything so
that is what the BJP should do now first
of all learn the lessons of 2024 learn
some
humility throw away the arrogance get
some good speakers who can come on the
national media not annoying people I'm
not saying everyone's annoying you you
need to have people who understand what
the common man and woman and child wants
you need people with some humility they
need to stop bringing in people from
other parties if you are bringing in
people
leaders corrupt allegedly corrupt
leaders some of them at least from other
parties then why should the Comm man
woman and child not vote for those
political parties instead of the
BJP and do something about the godamn
Bangladeshi and ringas otherwise you're
going to build the economy and these
people will outbreed you and then you
will hand over this great economy to the
Bangladesh's and
ringas why is this not been taken
seriously and when will you reform the
education system and when will you do
something about India's culture I've
been saying the ASI needs to be fixed no
these things don't matter India's
culture doesn't matter it's all economy
economy economy and election election
election well here we are today this is
what the count maners told you man
woman so yeah what they need to do now I
would say I am a geopolitical Observer I
know what happens when transitions go
wrong leadership transitions when
succession goes wrong
okay that's the common reason
historically for the death or decline
and eventual death of an Empire or
Dynasty or whatever it is so now they
need to transition they need to put in
place the plans for transition to the
next leader Mr Modi five years at most
it needs to now go to somebody who's
genuinely capable I would say we should
give Mr Yogi a chance I don't see
anybody else with that with that
fire in the BJP right now
that could be other people I'm sure that
I may not be aware of but I see Mr Yodi
Mr Yogi as the right next leader so
don't make it hard for him don't don't
try to Target him what happened in up is
not Mr Yogi's
fault okay what happened in up the
debacle that the BJP has faced in up is
not the fault of Mr Yogi don't try to
blame Mr Yogi for it Mr Yogi recommended
more than 30 candidates all of whom were
rejected so don't blame Mr Yogi for this
introspect Mr Yogi should be the next
leader he should be the Prime Minister
candidate from my perspective in 29 not
Dr J Shankar not somebody
else so that's what they need to do if
they want to continue and obviously the
there are other issues which I may not
be an expert to speak about so I'll not
speak about
them all right
says what will be the future of the Quad
if Trump comes to power the same thing
nothing will change nothing will change
it will be the same so it does see I say
this because it doesn't matter who comes
to power in the US whether it is Biden
whether it is Trump whether it is Kamal
Miss Miss Kamala Harris whether it is vi
vi whether it is anybody nothing changes
from a foreign policy perspective or a
military perspective nothing changes in
the US the US is
actually an authoritarian
uni party State masquerading as a
two-party democracy so nothing will
change Richard says what do you think
about anamalai I personally I personally
think he could be a great prime minister
of India look Mr anamalai has doesn't
have see I remember a few years ago my
friend ran labadia he asked me what do
you think about Mr Rahul Gandhi could he
be a good prime minister I said I do not
know because I do not have data I look
at things from a data d scientific
perspective Mr Gandhi Mr rul Gandhi has
no
experience
administering a
state he has no experience administering
a district or a municipality so we don't
know how good he is at administering
something so how can I say in the
absence of any data whether he'll be
good or bad similarly Anala is a great
speaker he's very charismatic he has his
right heart in the right place no doubt
he has been an IPS officer that is good
that is good so he knows how to deal
with people he's obviously doing well in
the party people all respect him so
obviously he knows how to deal with
people but we don't know how he will be
good or bad at administering a large
chunk of territory let's say Mr Modi
served two terms as gujarat's chief
minister and he proved himself so we
knew that he'll be a good prime minister
and he was he still is
so I don't know that about Mr anamalai I
think he could be great but I don't have
the data right now to verify whether
this hunch of mine and yours is correct
so I
think I would like to see him spend five
years as a chief minister before we can
think of him as a future Prime
Minister that needs to
happen Okay so that's my perspective we
have to be cautious and careful before
putting somebody as a prime Minister
candidate understand that you make a
mistake there you're going to if if it
goes wrong it's going to go wrong in a
tremendously bad manner because we're
talking about the highest position in
the country so we have to be cautious
you cannot let your emotions rule
overrule
logic so yeah I think aala could be
great in the future but I don't have
data to back that up we need to have a
test drive at least once when you buy a
new car you got to test drive it don't
so yeah there you have
it
uh Jatan says I have a Muslim friend in
from Indonesia called Indra there you
have it there are people in Indonesia
called Arjun who are Muslims uh we have
the the former ruler leader of Indonesia
the daughter of sukarno her name is
megawati sukaro she's a Muslim sukarno
himself was a Muslim so Indonesia you
will see lots of people with genuine
Sanskrit names the kind of names Indians
don't give to the children today nobody
in India will name their son Indra they
will use some weird name like God knows
what
okay so yeah that's the that's the thing
they still cherish their their their
Sanskrit uh connection and
Heritage okay
okay Dr J Shankar yeah says what are
your expectations from Modi 3.0 now my
expectations are very limited today I
expect that there will be no significant
deviation from the foreign policy that
we've already had the past 10 years or
the past 5 years if we continue on the
same trajectory of foreign policy we'll
be good that's number one number two
economic growth needs to keep on
happening that cannot be hampered
you manage your alliance partners and
their demands and whatnot in some way or
the other don't let it affect economic
growth don't let it a affect foreign
policy don't let it affect the military
buildup that we need to have because we
have tremendously dangerous threats on
our borders we have a nuclear powered
mad bunch of Madmen to our Northwest the
temporary artificial Nation Pakistan we
have Chinese occupied Tibet on the other
hand and that Chinese China is a way
more powerful Nation than India so we
have
to counterbalance this in some manner so
this is non-negotiable your foreign
policy cannot be affected Economic
Policy cannot be affected the economic
growth needs to keep happening the
military uh strength of India needs to
be bolstered apart from that I have no
other expectations I don't expect them
to do anything about the education
system or to do anything about culture
they had 10 years they didn't do it I
don't see them doing it any doing
anything anymore and the last
expectation is that there needs to be a
transition from Mr Modi to the next
leader of India Mr Modi he can last
these five years and that's it I don't
see I I would not like to see
him the Prime Minister candidate in
2029 that is that are my these are my
expectations from Modi 3.0 very
straightforward very simple
just don't don't do don't deviate too
much from where you are
today
okay HTI says it book recommendations
from for battle Tac strategy Etc yeah
nothing comes to my mind right now I've
read books about
uh um Roman battle formations and
tactics Greek things the fanks and
Alexander's battles and all um I don't
remember the names and all that right
now strategy yeah a couple of books by
Edward Luwak the grand strategy of the
Byzantine Empire the grand strategy of
the USSR Soviet Union and so on uh you
asked me on the spot about book nothing
will come to my mind because I've read
so many books you know like I don't know
who is the author of this quote that
I've had thousands of meals in my life I
don't remember most of them but they
made me who I am similarly I've read
thousands of books in my life I don't
remember them all but but they made me
who I am so I don't know but I will try
and dig up some books that I've read in
the past and I could maybe put out uh a
recommendation uh somewhere maybe in a
community note or something
okay okay let's
not aish says how do you manage to speak
with this much energy and passion if you
believe in something you speak about it
because you're passionate about it you
believe in that so I speak about things
that I believe in I don't speak about
things that I am not really well versed
in when you do that I suppose you have
energy
passion uh
okay rudra says if the Constitution is
not ratified by the people of India can
a party like the BJP challenge it and
change it through the Supreme Court of
India do further integration of Nepal
okay Nepal um see it's not if it is a
fact that the constitution has not been
ratified by the people of India now what
do I mean when I say that the
constitution has not been ratified by
the people of India what do I mean by
that
it means that when a bunch of old guys
sit together and draft a constitution
once the Constitution is drafted before
you write we the people you have to
offer the Constitution to the public
here it is read it go through it and
then you need to have a referendum which
means you have to ask the people now
that you have had six months to read
this or one year to read this do you
agree with this do you accept this as
your Constitution or do you reject it
yes or no that's a godamn vote that's a
referendum that needs to happen and if
the people say yes we accept it then it
means they have ratified
it that is how it works in a real
democracy and this constitution has been
shoved down our throats
undemocratically do you understand
that's what I mean when I say that the
constitution of India is illegitimate it
has never been ratified by the people of
India
bring me a single constitutional expert
who can challenge
this bring me anybody who can challenge
what I'm saying here they
want now can the can a party like the
BJP challenge it and change it through
the Supreme Court of
India party like the BJP worships the
constitution of India if you see Mr Modi
he has
actually actually worshiped the
constitution of India because it is what
brought him to power they won't ever
challenge the Constitution
I don't see that
happening and I don't know about the
Supreme Court of India they also owe
everything to the Constitution they
won't challenge it and if somebody tries
to challenge it they will throw it out
and they may perhaps sanction the person
who tries to challenge the constitution
of
India so this Constitution which has
been shoved down our throats
undemocratically there is no as far as I
know there is no clause or whatever in
the Constitution that allows you to
change it unless you have a 2/3 majority
in the parliament of India
and there's whole process behind that
and once Mr Modi tried to tried to enact
something the national Judiciary
something thing some judicial reform it
it passed through everything it passed
through the entire Democratic process
and the Supreme Court rejected that and
Mr Modi accepted
that so what can I say it is a millstone
around our neck this
Constitution and I don't know when if
whatever it will be removed but it is
not something that you can attribute to
We the People of India it is a bunch of
old guys who got together in a
room okay and drafted this constitution
I believe even Dr edar was not satisfied
with the Constitution if I'm not
mistaken I have not
read too much about Mr edar but if I
recall correctly he was not satisfied
with the Constitution
anyway that's where we are integration
of Nepal has nothing to do with the
Constitution mck Lovin says why is our
government obsessed with Western
architecture aodha airport is the only
modern Indian style architecture I
believe there's some some airport in
Kerala also Ki or kic cord or something
that has a good Indian style
architecture I believe there are a few
airports here and there that have
something the problem is these architect
are all mentally colonized and uh these
whatever designs they propos they are at
the end of the day uh approved by IAS
officers now we have some fantastic IAS
officers in the country but the majority
are a bunch of Dum
Dums okay mentally coron people who go
who go through the IAS exams in which
you study romula toer Iran Habib you see
the the lot that studies history they
are so ment
colonized when you have such people who
approve the design they're going to
approve the worst of the designs the
most de deracinated designs something
that that is a poor imitation of
something in the west so that's what we
get and the politicians they leave these
things these matters to the is officers
so that's what you get in this country
so we need to raise our standards how do
you raise the standards by changing
systems by changing by reforming systems
by reforming institutions by reforming
the God damned education system which is
utter trash but we won't do that right
our politicians our leaders who we elect
have no don't see that as a priority
because this system has brought them to
power so why meddle with that I want to
stay in
power this brought me to Power why
should I change
it
okay chasti asks a question about
geography geography I like it
so kir says if the Himalayas did not
exist would Delhi experience snowfall
similar to places like Texas given that
both regions are located at similar
latitudes excellent question now let's
take a look at the map let's take a look
at something else that me put something
on screen yes
um okay give me a second let me present
something on the screen windy.com when
we look at the subcontinent of India so
this is the current situation let's go
to temperature shall we o laa look at
temperature worldwide so right now we
are I think cooler than various parts of
Africa in the Arabian Peninsula but a
few days ago India was the hottest place
in the world and if you look just north
of India Chinese occupied the Tibet you
can see the temperatures are much much
much cooler just a few kilometers north
of the Heatwave situation and what's
what's the thing in between it's the
great Himalayan mountain chain the
Himalayan Mountain Range so it is the
Himalayas that prevent the cold air from
the Tibetan Plateau flowing into India
and they also prevent the hot air from
the Indian subcontinent mixing with the
cold air of the Tibetan plateau and the
Himalayas are also instrumental in the
uh in what we call the Indian rainy
season so the Himalayas are one of the
root causes of this cyclical weather
phenomenon called the Indian in rainy
season so if the Himalayas did not exist
then Delhi and the Northern parts of
India would experience similar climate
certainly
to perhaps places like
Texas uh if you see Southern India has
uh and and Central India has a climate
that's very similar to that of Mexico
which is at the same
latitudes so it is possible that uh the
region around Delhi would have a similar
climate as Texas it's possible but there
are other factors also because every
geography is different but overall I
what you're saying actually makes sense
so yeah good question good question but
you can't do away with the Himalayan
Mountain Range it is it's a fact of life
it's been there for at least 50 million
years and it is something that has that
defines the climatic and geographical
conditions that are characteristic
characteristic of the Indian
subcontinent all right
uh rajit says will relations with the
Middle East suffer now what would happen
to the Indians who are working or
planning to go there because BJP did not
manage to strengthen our ties I don't
see any anything going wrong with our
relations with the Middle East I see the
alliance partners of the BJP within the
NDA want some some benefits obviously
this is the great opportunity they've
been praying for now they've got it so
obviously they will try and extract as
much possible as many concessions as
possible from Mr Modi Ministries and
whatever special status for this state
or that state and this ministry that
Plum post all that they will want beyond
that I don't think they will try and
unless there
is some
foreign relationship or whatever beyond
that I don't see the foreign policy
changing too much so as far as it it
goes with as far as our relations with
the Middle East go Nations like friendly
Nations like Saudi Arabia the UAE Etc
Oman and so on I don't see too much
changing so uh the ties are pretty
strong the relationship is very good the
bilateral relationships are all very
good I don't see that changing too much
so our relations with the Middle East I
don't see them
suffering in any way and Indians who are
working there and planning to go there
can just go ahead with their plans no
issues all
right Malik s says have you read Think
and Grow Rich by nepo in Hill if yes
then is it good I haven't read it but I
have listened to it I had an audio book
and long long ago when I should travel
overnight by train to go to some place
or the other I would listen to that and
lie down and yeah so I have listened to
it and if I recall correctly it was it
was very interesting it was pretty
interesting overall I would recommend
that people read it it's a good book
it's one of the all-time great classic
books about uh personal finance and
things like that so yeah I would say
it's a good
book
uh okay let's see what other questions
we have
Annabeth Jackson says why is the ASI
archaeological Survey of India so
underfunded the problem from my
perspective certainly it is underfunded
it's it's something to do with history
and culture so why would the government
fund that they don't care about history
and culture the
government the real problem is not that
they are underfunded the real problem is
that they simply don't care about what
is really important they will prioritize
the
upkeep and re renov
Etc of the uh architecture that the
foreigners left behind in India the
foreign occupiers of India of the past
10 or so centuries the Turks whatever
they built is something sacred to the
ASI and whatever the British
architecture the British look behind
that is sacred to the ASI and they're
going to spend all of their efforts and
money and funds and resources in you
know in this work when it comes to
uncovering the true history of India
they don't want to touch it with with a
100 foot pole when it comes to
Excavating dwarka the undersea
exploration of dwarka they won't do that
it's it's not been done for the past two
three decades and who knows what the
situation is of the underwater city Mr
Modi went there recently he got some
nice photographs and all he did a scuba
dive and all but what about funding the
ASI and funding and restarting U the
archaeological work over there nothing
nothing so it is because of a lack of
political will the politicians the
leaders of this country simply don't
care about this that's all I can
say technical an says will Yogi be able
to secure the CM chief minister position
again in the next election in the up in
in utar Pradesh seeing the current
scenario I think Mr Yogi is the best
leader uttar Pradesh has had in decades
he has done such tremendous work in the
state obviously there's still room for
improvement I'm sure there is a
considerable amount of room for
improvement but what he has already
achieved this tremendous now will he be
able to secure the CM position again
depends on his leaders in the BJP he is
obviously at he's after all a member of
the BJP so the BJP High command will
decide that when the next election come
come around who's going to be the CM
candidate that's how it works in
India
so it's it's going to be probably Mr
Modi Mr sha and whoever is the BJP
president who will decide whether Mr
Yogi continues or not now this current
debacle that we witnessed
yesterday okay that other parties got
more seats than the BJP in utar Pradesh
in the 2024 general election it is it
has nothing to do with Mr Yogi it is not
a reflection on Mr Yogi's governance
Deli always votes for one political
party in the local elections and it
always votes for the BJP in the central
elections the same voters vote
diametrically differently whether
depending on whether it's a state
election or Central election so this was
a central election it was a general
election it has nothing to do with local
politics it has nothing to do with Mr
Yogi's governance I think he is the best
leader up has had for a long time but at
the end of the day the BJP High command
will decide if Mr Yogi is given the
chance to serve as CM again I would
actually like Mr Yogi to be the next PM
candidate in
29 but yeah it all depends on
them by says Where are all the Young
Fresh Faces in Indian politics it seems
that Indian youth diaspora is as is much
more Indian than India's own youth can
the education system be changed you
can't go do
politics you
know what is the Hallmark of a truly
great leader apart from the look what is
the non-negotiable thing that quality
that a leader must have the first the
most important quality a leader must
must have is that a leader must win
success is non-negotiable if you don't
succeed you are not worthy of being a
leader so success is number one but
another very important Hallmark of a
great leader is that he or
she nurtures and
creates a bunch of other Junior leaders
who can one day take over from him or
her okay okay so the a great leader
creates more great leaders who can then
take over who can be the next generation
of leadership so is that happening right
now yeah we have one potential great
leader in India who is Mr Yogi there is
another potential leader that people
speak about Mr anamalai but he needs to
First prove prove himself as the CM of a
state which is very far from happening
right now but it's not his fault uh and
who are the other young leaders that we
can think of I'm sure there are a few we
don't want another 70y old guy no
offense to Mr Modi he should have been
the PM candidate in 2009 actually but he
wasn't allowed to so yeah he he's done
what he can and he served the nation
greatly of course but it's time to look
at the next step
so so the problem is most most of the
Indian political parties are dynastic
parties so they will marginalize anybody
who has actual leadership potential in
favor of the the the family that that
owns the party essentially right so many
of these political parties are dynastic
polic parties the BJP isn't which is
good so one would expect that the BJP
would throw up lots of young fresh faces
in politics we see a few but one would
hope to see more right so clearly
there's something that needs to be
improved I agree with you can the
education system be changed you need
strong leadership for that to happen and
there was very strong leadership the
past 10 years first you had what both
both times Mr Modi had a complete
majority for the BJP but he didn't do it
he did not do
it so if he could not do it when he had
absolute majority who's going to do it
now we have this ghastly RTE act right
to Education Act that actually uh it has
all these
horrible
um Clauses and all that so that could
have been amended they didn't do it so
it's there was simply no will to do what
to to address cultural and
civilizational issues through education
nothing so yeah there we
are main or man I don't know what says
do you think there was a foreign in
influence in the Indian election of
course there was of course of course
there was foreign interference influence
in the Indian elections first of all all
these Western media Outlets like the BBC
the guardian the New York Post the New
York Times whatever Washington Post
Washington Times all of these they threw
out a constant barrage of criticism
against India that India's democracy is
under threat India's becoming more
authoritarian and those english-
speaking Indians who read all this will
get influenced by that there was that
right then there is the the situation in
a place like Manipur for example which
makes the current government look very
weak right this huge influx of of
foreign Nationals into
Manipur who are
and who automatically get SC or St
status the moment they they set down
Roots 10 hundreds of thousands have have
poured into Manipur over the past I
don't know few
decades and all this is this is a
geopolitical game that's been played to
to to to weaken India in in in the Far
East so there was that that is a
geopolitical game that's been
played by The Usual Suspects
destabilizing Burma destabilizing India
that is fore an influence
then all these things that happened the
khalistani riots and whatnot in Delhi
the shahinbag thing whatever that's all
foreign influence I assure you of that
then all these so-called influencers and
YouTubers who have become so popular of
late that is foreign influence I assure
you of that there's so much more so
obviously it's there it is very much
there and I'm sure it has actually had
an effect this time in 2014 it was the
BJP that won the online battle the
social social media battle but they in
2024 10 years later they have abjectly
surrendered the for the social media
battle and they've lost they've lost who
who do they have to blame for that will
they blame the Indian voter for that
they should have nurtured an ecosystem
of so-called influencers they did not do
that there are so many good influencers
on on the right side on the
nationalistic side of the Divide but the
BJP did not support them I'm not talking
about me by the way okay I'm not talking
about me I'm talking about there are
there are I don't deal with I don't
speak about politics do I National
politics I'm not talking about me there
are so many good people who talk about
culture who talk about politics who talk
about the national interest what
happened to string VOD see how what
happened to him his his channel was
deleted did the government help him no
didn't help him uh there's this guy
called arihant vad he does great work
does he have any support from the
government I don't think so uh there is
uh Ajit bti there is uh pram great great
man Captain yeah and so on do they get
any support from the government no but
these other influences is anti-nationals
they I assure you they have more than
sufficient funding and there are these
fake
nationalists okay a bunch of whom got
the most prestigious awards given by the
hands of the Prime Minister himself I
was there in that function I was
nominated but I did not win it has
nothing to do with me not winning or
anything I don't care but the these fake
nationalists some of them not all of
them all of them are not fake
nationalists some of them who then later
go and tweet all eyes on Rafa H these
people were given Awards by the by the
hands of the Prime Minister himself so
this is what they have done they are
clueless the people who decide these
Awards they honor the the wrong
persons they promote the wrong people
and they have failed in creating an
ecosystem that is a genuinely
nationalist ecosystem there are so many
influencers who have their hearts in the
right places who are doing what they can
with whatever little resources they have
but they are not helped they get no help
whatsoever you are on your own and we
will honor and and promote those who are
actually opportunists and fake
nationalists it is so annoying it is so
unfortunate a bunch of Clueless losers
that that's what I would say 10 years I
did not criticize the government 10
years because because unfortunately my
my my voice matters and if I do some
criticism it could end up having some
tiny influence on things so I don't I
didn't want to do
it but yeah that's where we are very
very frustrating I've been so frustrated
10 years with what's not being
done yeah I know I know some people are
naming those influencers and you are
right adya says would it be better to
have a presidential election or Governor
type in India also
look if you look at India's geography
India is not a small nation state India
is a gigantic nation state it's a
subcontinent sized nation state when you
have a nation of that size you cannot
decentralize power and have these this
federal system you need to centralize
power in at least some aspects in some
respects a a nation of this size needs
to have a very strong power center you
can of course have lots of
decentralization when it comes to local
governance and all that but overall the
major decision- making has to happen at
the top so you need a presidential
system if you want to remain a democracy
you can you should India actually would
do much better with presidenti because
see in a coalition government The
Government Can disintegrate any time why
do you want an unstable political system
why elect and why can't people elect
their prime minister directly why is it
always indirect you can only elect vote
for the local MP and then all these MPS
will get together and decide who's going
to be the Prime Minister why why can't
the Indian voter have the right to
choose his or her prime minister
candidate who they want to vote for why
why such a ridiculous system has been
shoved down India's throats the throats
of the Indian people so I would say that
we should have a presidential system
because that will give you five years or
four years whatever the term is of
stability just one person ruling and he
or she can decide that cabinet and
nobody can bring that down and there can
be so that will be a genuine separation
of powers you know you need separation
between the Executive Branch the
legislative branch and the Judiciary
right now there is no separation between
the the executive and the
legislative why so yes a presidential
system would be much better but we don't
have it we have all the wrong things in
this country all the wrong
things sahil says what do you think
about the upcoming harana assembly
elections I don't have the first clue
about what's going on there I'm so sorry
I don't observe local local state
politics I don't know I'm so sorry
so shant says now India is becoming a
major weapons exporter and armenia's
involvement in the nagoro kabak conflict
uh India's weapons are going to be used
on a big scale do you see India as a
major power player in this market that's
one thing Mr Modi has done very well
India is now becoming a
genuine exporter of Weapons
Systems and we have done that Visa
Armenia Armenia is being while it's
being threatened with complete
extinction by the Turks and the
the nagoro kabak or or
arak conflict so we have exported
weapons to Armenia Radars and oh whole
pinaka missiles and and much more and
it's going to be used so it's good I
would like to see India emerge as a
major play player in the U in this
market for sure and Mr Modi has done uh
tremendous amount of work in setting up
the conditions to make this happen so
this needs to continue this needs to
continue Raj chobra says will Yogi G be
accepted as the leader of Barat some
people feel threatened by him because of
his Pro hind stature so those who feel
threatened by Pro hinda are the ones who
uh don't want Hinduism in India in
Bat there's always going to be such
people that what can you do about them
can you please everybody in life as as
as an individual human being you can't
please everybody you can't please all
your friends you can't please all your
family you can't please all your
co-workers you can't please all your
bosses you can't please all your all the
people who report to you you can't
please all your employees as a
politician you can't please all the
voters you don't want to please
everybody you please though you need to
have a clear set of principles and a
clear ideology and you work for that and
then if you're good enough people will
vote for you or not so Mr Yogi obviously
he knows this way better than me he
doesn't have to please everybody and and
whether he is accepted by the people as
the leader of bhat depends on the people
of bat and it depends on the gods so
that's what I would say those who feel
threatened for by him well maybe they
should he doesn't he has not done
anything against anybody who was
innocent right he's brought down home
bulldozers you know all those bulldozer
action against criminals so if you're a
criminal and you feel threatened by him
then don't be a
criminal it has nothing to do with hinda
nothing nothing at all from my
perspective the way I see
it
okay one
second all
right this is by uh of interesting uh
username is the India story and the
sanatan dma's Renaissance over and is
reclaiming our territories illegally
occupied by Pakistan and China still on
the cards okay India story is not over
it has taken a temporary
setback okay and don't blame the Indian
voter for that the Indian voter is the
Indian voter so sanatan dh's Renaissance
is not over I think it will still go on
it will take time everything every all
good things take time the India story is
not over sanatan dhas Renaissance is not
over I hope Mr Modi uses this five years
very well to to as a transition period
to the next set of leaders or the the
next leader hopefully
uh is reclaiming our territories
illegally occupied by Pakistan and
Kashmir and and China still on the cards
so I've been saying this for a long time
don't worry about Pakistan ubad Kashmir
and so on we just have to keep growing
the economy and eventually we'll become
so big and so powerful that this will
happen on its own Pakistan is a
temporary artificial Nation it will
disintegrate on its own which is why we
need a strong India and we had the
chance of a strong Modi 3.0 but didn't
happen anyway we are a 10,000 year
civilization we will have will'll be
around at least 10,000 years this is
just a small part of our history a small
chapter in our history so we don't want
to go to war with anybody right now next
20 years just focus on growing the
economy and reforming the nation I think
that's what needs to happen eventually
everything will come back to us so P
will eventually be reintegrated with
with India Pakistan eventually will
disintegrate because of the sins of
their own Armed Forces who are ruling
the country like like a bunch of tyrants
and when it comes to China it may take
longer but that will also happen because
China historically doesn't have any
presence in this region and uh China's
growth story is also U it's it's it's on
the decline now so yeah I I despite
what's happened yesterday I would urge
everybody despite the frustrations
despite whatever to remain optimistic
and work hard work hard at an individual
level it will all go
fine
okay what else geopolitical dub says
there's news that France increased the
cost of the the Rafal plane is that so
okay I've not seen that they can do it
if they sense that the the other party
is interested if there is a demand for
it you can certainly increase prices
it's all about supply and demand basic
economics if something is in high demand
that item it's its value goes up so
obviously they they they can raise the
price the the the cost of the raal
perfectly legitimate if they have done
it it's up to us to respond do we are we
desperate do we need that I think we
should have a whole bunch more Rafal
whatever it costs obviously we should
negotiate just don't give into all the
demands you can give them some
incentives that we'll buy 2,000 Rafal
you set up the whole Factory in India
and transfer all the technology I'm just
saying we don't want 2,000 of them maybe
100 or whatever India wants to buy
yeah yeah so if if that is the case if
they have increased the cost it's a
legitimate
tactic
okay all right let's
uh the says will the BJP become less
bold in the pursuit of its internal and
foreign policy agendas these include
implementation of CAA NRC UCC and it's
Bolder foreign policy strategies I don't
see too much of an impact on the foreign
policy strategies on India's foreign
policy I don't see too much of an impact
of the coalition government on the
economic policies also when it comes to
internal matters like CAA NRC UC I don't
I think it may not happen I may be wrong
if I'm wrong if I'm proven to be wrong
it's great I'll be happy but I think the
likelihood has decreased now the
probability of CA nrca Etc happening may
be lower I hope I'm wrong I hope it's
still happens but it could
certainly uh take take uh take an impact
but I hope that the foreign policy won't
change too much and the economic
policies also won't change too much I
don't see too many gigantic reforms
coming in now that can only happen if
you are completely on your own with a
full majority not
happened all
right s says why don't you color your
hair how Bing is it to have to color
your hair every two weeks cuz the hair
grows and then you to do it again and
again how do I care it is what it is I
don't need to do that I've never people
sometimes ask me I I don't care I'm just
fine the way it
is I'm a lazy guy I'm a lazy guy I I I'm
bored to even shave every day you
know okay
uh Deepak says please tell about Diego
Garcia an island of the British Indian
Ocean territory I have a whole video on
that so go to my channel go to the
videos and there is one about the chos
archipelago c h a g oos chos in which I
have given a detailed explanation of
what this Diego Garcia thing is how it
is illegally occupied by the British and
the Americans how the international
courts have all asked them to withdraw
and bring the indigenous allow the
indigenous population to to come back
but they don't do it and the reason is
the Americans have a gigantic military
base over there in Diego Garcia since we
have not opened the map today at all as
far as I can recall let's do that let's
go to the map where's the map here's the
map there can't be an askit session
without the map being open at least once
so here we have it this is the map so
the Diego Garcia the chos archipelago is
part of the lakshadweep chos Ridge and
this is the archipelago okay let's me
zoom out so that you can locate it it's
south of the equator in the Indian Ocean
region just south of the Maldives it
actually belongs to morous it is
illegally occupied by the Americans and
the British technically British
territory but actually American
territory and if you if you go zoom in
then you will see that the Americans
have a massive military presence here
okay so you have this here A Big Air
Base Diego Garcia
NSF and uh
Port also so the the port over here is
is capable of of holding of of
accommodating aircraft carriers and the
airport over here can accommodate the
the heaviest of of uh of Transport
Aircraft Etc this is a very important us
strategic base in the region and they
acquired this base in I think 1973 or
something after their debacle in 1971
when they were unable to prevent India
from liberating Bangladesh the Americans
wanted to to see the continuation of the
Pakistani genocide Pakistani of the
genocide of Hindus in East Pakistan at
the hands of the Pakistani military and
they sent an aircraft carrier strike
group in the Bay of Bengal the British
also sent an aircraft carrier strike
group to bully India but the Soviets
sent a fleet of nuclear submarines and
that was able to deter the Americans and
the British which is why India was able
to liberate Bangladesh from the genoci
titled Pakistani monsters in 1971 so the
Americans realized that they need a
place from which they can project power
in this region which is why they
acquired Diego Garcia in
1973 and the locals the natives were
evicted ejected from here by force by
the British and they still remain in
Exile that is in short the story of fos
and the British Indian Ocean territory
and Theo garciaa and if you want to know
it in Greater detail check out my video
on the topic you can see it in my list
of videos it it came out what couple of
months ago or so this year
itself
okay jph peda says ancient India had
great history and culture like women
wrote many of the hymns of the rig great
Drainage Systems Great Cuisine and women
were worshiped exalted India yes
absolutely true it is true I thought
there was a question but it's a
statement I agree tell me give show me
one religious tradition in the world
where a significant portion of the
holiest text is written is authored by
women I'll wait I think I'll have to
wait forever does Christianity have that
no no no no no does any of the other
wonderful abrahamic religions have that
no no no no no it's only Hinduism that
has that okay so that is true and
obviously all the other things that you
are mentioning you are right sir all
right okay um
okay Adit Adit bachari says the I Indian
Air Force is Way Beyond The People's
Liberation Army Air Force the Chinese
Air Force with its deployment of G20
fighters in Tibet Chinese occupied Tibet
India if is struggling to get even 4.5
generation Fighters which is the Rafal
and whatever else what will happen in an
emergency situation in the upcoming
years okay let's say the Chinese decide
to go to war with India go to the map
once again
so if you look at the Chinese positions
in occupied Tibet you have a couple of
uh what do they call there is Lassa
there
shat where they have air bases there is
enari where is angari somewhere here so
let's look at Lassa and let's look at
shiat and shat has decided to disappear
okay here it is so they have air bases
here and they have j20 fighter planes
Etc that are positioned over
here uh okay I will not go and search
for the air bases because it will take
time but they they have all that here so
let's say the Chinese decide that they
are going to go to war with India what
do we do e emergency situation we're
going to have to cope somehow manage
somehow we do have certain advantages
from the perspective of terrain
geography all that we're going to have
to use missiles overall the Chinese are
way more powerful than us so it's going
to be we're going to have to act very
rapidly and we're going to have to take
the fight to Chinese occupied territory
you can't fight a defensive war against
China historically China does very
poorly when it has to fight a war on its
own territory so we'll have to do it the
right way and and Factor all our
shortcomings into the mix and and and
don't underestimate the Indian AR Armed
Forces despite the overall superiority
the CH Chinese have they have some
shortcoming and drawbacks like the
isolated status of Tibet there's only
one Railway line and one one or two
roads that connect mainland China with
occupied Tibet you take that out there's
going to be trouble in in Tibet Chinese
will find it hard to to hold on to Tibet
so you have to take the battle to the to
the Chinese occupied territory and all
that overall it's going to be an uphill
task for India if the Chinese go decide
to go to war with India but we should
not underestimate our Armed Forces
and of course we need to acquire we need
to bolster our military strength we need
to acquire the latest Technologies we
need to
acquire large quantities of fighter
planes of missiles of arms and
ammunition and weapon systems of all
kinds we have to do that and we need to
accelerate that process I am not
satisfied with what's happened in the
past 10 years we should have done more
than that but okay we're still doing
well we have done okay we've done good
the way the Border roads and
infrastructure have been built up so all
that is
good
okay now what else the says how do
Indians prevent their long-term
interests from being severely endangered
by the artificial demographic
re-engineering that's in process and
which NRC and UCC were supposed to
remedy Indians cannot do anything the
government has to do
it the government has to do it the
government has done nothing Bangladesh
are still pouring into India 10 years
ago they were saying there were 50
million Bangladesh's in India you go to
any city in India most cities will have
these Rika drivers and whatnot all
speaking Bangladeshi Bengali everywhere
they're everywhere and the government
has done nothing to stop it that is one
of the biggest failures of the Modi
government they have done nothing to
stop the influx of Bangladesh is they've
not sent any Bangladesh's back as far as
I can
see should have happened right 10 years
they had 10 years it's still happening
and now we have a situation in Manipur
where lots of foreigners are coming in
and settling down and claiming to be
Indians and getting a scheduled tribe
status while the actual indigenous of
people of Manipur are being completely
marginalized another failure so all that
is happening what can Indians do about
this what can the common Indian citizen
do about it nothing it is the
government's job to do this and they
have not done that they have failed
okay what else do we
have P says do you think Punjab is
moving towards a mess Christian
conversions khalistani movement Etc yes
yes very rapid rampant large scale
Christian
conversions six sick people are
converting to
Christianity incredible and the
khalistani movement something should
have been done about that nothing has
been done so yeah I think Punjab is
moving towards a
mess and something should have been done
about it but nothing has been
done
okay
uh a man with no
[Music]
name yeah good good Trilogy okay do you
agree with the thoughts of Julius Iola
and Yukio Mishima on modernity and the
decline of culture are we going to talk
are we going to witness what they talked
about soon in India any book
recommendation uh yeah they much of what
they have said is correct Yuko Mishima
was all about Japanese nationalism and I
spoke about him in one of the last
week's episodes decline of culture
modernity Mo look modernity is fine
modern technology all that stuff but
modernity doesn't mean that you reject
your ancestral culture and just get rid
of it that's not
modernity in India modernity means
becoming more westernized which means
becoming more woke that's not modernity
modernity means you use the latest
Innovations in
technology and use that to make your
life better to have better living
standards but you don't you don't
discard your culture that's not
modernity but today everyone believes
that is being modern and being
westernized is being modern affecting
Western mannerisms and Western accents
is being modern so yeah and and decline
of culture so I agree with these aspects
of what people have said I have not
really read Iola maybe I should get some
expert on Julius Iola on this channel do
a podcast a conversation with that
person I can think of people of one or
two people Julius Iola yes yuk Mishima
I've read
so I I recommended one of his books last
time it's a it's a set of four novels
which kind of describes
what Japan culturally Etc went through
it was a great writer Mishima so it
could happen in India whatever they
spoke about and so on any book
recommendations uh read Ebola and Mish I
would say I
guess okay let's take a couple of more
questions before we end today's uh live
stream swar says if the Indian education
system is restructured how would you
like it to be I have two or three
episodes in which I've spoken only about
the education system ask abijit around
episodes 35 to 45 somewhere around that
time you want to really know my thoughts
on this you watch those episodes in
which I've gone into great detail about
what should happen how it should be done
what should be done and so
on
okay vom says is Germany good for
Education was thinking of applying to
universities abroad to study mostly for
St stem subjects what's your opinion on
the education system abroad overall I
think Germany has a good education
system I haven't seen it personally but
when hears it's a good education system
uh Germans have usually been at the
Forefront of technology engineering and
all that and obviously that has
something to do with the quality of
their education system so I would say
Germany is good so yeah that's what I
can say overall education outside of
India is exponentially better than the
garbage education system that we have in
India so if you get the opportunity do
go abroad and study and get your degree
and do
well shinki says what's your favorite
movie I don't have one favorite movie a
whole bunch of favorite movies I can I
can recommend 50 movies or something The
Man With No Name Trilogy Good the Bad
and the Ugly a fist full of dollars and
so on that's good Sergio Leon films a
great uh Bud Spencer teren Hill movies
that no one remembers today great movies
I like comedy I like science fiction I
like action I like all genres of
movies so maybe I should do a video
about that you know a video in which I
recommend let's say 50 movies or
something
okay all right let's
uh b b says your opinion on the people
of Kalinga both Lok SAA and bhan SAA BJP
won bidhan SAA was unexpected uh good
look it whether they voted for the BJP
or not that's not how I determine how I
shape my view about the people of a
state Kalinga has a tremendous history
glorious history they were at the
Forefront of of taking India's culture
and civilization all across Eastern Asia
for the past 3,000 years Kalinga is is a
great great place great history Rich
culture immense contributions to Indian
civilization so I think the people of
Kalinga are a great people and it's it's
sad to see the State the the condition
of the state of odisha Kalinga utkal Etc
today should have the people should have
gotten got a better deal so yeah they
have voted for the BJP good I hope the
BJP does something good for the state
and the
people all right all right all right all
right fortified with G spirit says
what's the idea of studying how's the
idea of studying medicine in Italy I
don't know much about the education
system in
Italy uh so I don't know I don't know I
I I'm not in in this world right now of
of looking at which country has what
what kind of education system for what
subject I don't really know I sure it
will be better than what you get in
India that's what I can
assume but uh I personally don't know
about
medicine and studying medicine in so I
can't answer
really geopolitical du says do you see
the possibility of Donald Trump making
coming back to Power do you think the
Deep state will allow that I don't think
the Deep state will allow that I was of
the opinion that Donald Trump was very
lucky during his first term that he that
he did not get
1963 if you know what I mean I don't
think they will allow him to come back
to Power we can already see the way he's
being
treated you know he's being
uh
uh he they are going after him through
every means possible he was recently
indicted for some something or the other
some crime he may even have to go to
jail for that jury rigged jury found him
guilty allegedly rigged jury so there is
political persecution in the US like you
you will not see in other countries so I
don't think they will allow him to come
back to
Power okay let us
uh high five repor says is Jerome Powell
often dubbed the man who speaks who
speaks money more powerful than the US
president in terms of economic decisions
his speeches often cause significant
Market volatility look I cannot
speculate it's possible I know for a
fact that the US president is not the
most powerful entity in the country the
US president right now it's so obvious
Biden Biden you think is running the
country obviously he's not running the
country so there is a bunch of people a
group of people somewhere at some level
in the US who actually run the country
and maybe jome powerwell is could be
perhaps one of them but you can't say
for sure because you don't know what's
going on deep beneath the surface but
it's possible it is certainly possible
PE says your views on Turkey want wed to
join bricks good for them let's have
everybody let's have turkey let's have
Pakistan let's have Botswana let's have
Ghana no standards come on
they would obviously want to be part of
this they want to have their feet in
every bucket one one foot in Nato one
foot in bricks and enjoy the both of
best of both things and you can also
serve as a spy in bricks and report back
to your daddy Big Daddy in the US so I
think
well I don't I don't think it's a good
idea to to admit turkey into bricks it's
as bad as an idea as allowing Pakistan
to become a member of bricks turkey
Pakistan I I see them as more or less
the same kind of
entity okay
um lots of questions as
always okay
let's nikil says questions from X no I'm
only looking at the YouTube live stream
I only have one screen in front of me I
can't look at different set of questions
coming from different places so
unfortunately I can only look at the
YouTube comments YouTube uh live
chat all right
uh what else do we have what else do we
have can you make a video with book
recommendations okay Annabeth I think
it's a good idea to do that it's been a
long time since I made a video about
book recommendations I will do that I'll
take it up thank you for that
recommendation all
right
he
okay kashish says is is studying abroad
better than studying it in
IIT maybe look today in the iits the
iits are no longer what they used to be
before they ruined the iits with the
implementation of reservations IIT used
to be the some of the best educational
institutions in the world but today
they're not even in the top 100 so maybe
studying abroad is better perhaps than
studying at the I at at an IIT there are
some iits which are still great in India
but uh most of those I would say are no
longer at the same standards they used
to be 20 years ago so yeah if you get
into a good college University in a good
country I think you may want to take it
seriously
all right okay I think I'm going to stop
here
now
uh one second hey Kenneth uh I've never
seen you on the live stream before I've
seen your comments before so thank you
so much I really appreciate your
viewership and much love to the whole of
the Philippines from
India and
uh Shri okay let's end with this
question Shari Tada says is it all doom
and Loom no let's be optimistic let's
positive uh I I think this episode may
have come about come across as a more
gloomy and pessimistic episode because I
have aired expressed
my frustration a bit with Mr Modi and
his government his governance of the
past 10 years but overall I think I am
still glad that Mr Modi will continue as
prime minister I'm glad that the NDA
will form a government it's not all doom
and gloom it will not be a powerful Modi
this time it will be a more
uh weakened Mr Modi but overall I think
the foreign policy won't change much
economic growth will still hopefully be
on trajectory so let's be optimistic and
end on an optimistic note I think it
will still go well let us all be
optimistic and most importantly let's
keep on going forward and doing whatever
we can in our own capacity to contribute
to society to the country but first of
all let's develop ourselves and keep
raising our standards because if we all
raise our standards societ collectively
acquires higher standards so let's let's
end on that I don't think it's all doom
and gloom let us be positive let us be
optimistic all right my dear friends
thank you so much for all the questions
I'm going to end it here apologize to
those of you whose questions I could not
answer but you will always have the
opportunity in future sessions to ask
your questions and hopefully I I get to
see all of your questions thank you so
much I'll see you in the next live
stream keep raising your standards thank
you bye